<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JBang on Apache Camel</title>
    <link>https://camel.apache.org/categories/JBang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JBang on Apache Camel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://camel.apache.org/categories/JBang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three Apache Camel JBang Videos</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/2023/10/jbang-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/2023/10/jbang-video/</guid>
      <description>For the past year, we have worked on Camel JBang, that is becoming ready to be more widespread known among Camel users.&#xA;In this blog I just want to quickly refer to a number of recent video recordings of Camel JBang in action.&#xA;Apache Camel 4.0 with Camel JBang MQTT demo - by Claus, How to quickly build a Camel prototype with MQTT using Docker Camel JBang - Run Camel as Script using JBang by Jasvinder, with first impressions of Camel JBang Apache Camel JBang - Reload quickly running Camel via copy/paste - by Claus, a poor man&amp;rsquo;s iPaaS with Apache Camel Karavan and Camel JBang </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to test an Integration for Camel K</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/blog/2022/11/camel-k-jbang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/blog/2022/11/camel-k-jbang/</guid>
      <description>Testing is probably one of those operations we use to repeat most of the time while building any application. Applications in Camel world are no difference. With the advent of Camel JBang, we have a unified place that can be used to perform our testing/fine tuning locally before moving to a higher environment.&#xA;During the last years of development, we have noticed that testing or fine tuning an integration directly connected to a Cloud Native environment can result a bit cumbersome.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
