<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Apache Camel</title>
    <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Apache Camel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://camel.apache.org/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Articles</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/articles/</guid>
      <description>Camel Videos Apache Camel and ActiveMQ at UPS May 2024 where UPS presented their use of Apache Camel and ActiveMQ on OpenShift processing tens of billions messages a day. Quarkus Insights #110: Quarkiverse Extension Spotlight of Apache Camel November 2022 where Apache Camel was presented on the Quarkus webcast (1h session). Cloud Native My Camel: from Low Code to Pro Code, inject Serverless &amp;amp; Cloud Native Goodness by Michael Costello from June 2022, 45-min session on low-code Apache Camel, Camel K and demo with Karavan, the Camel UI designer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/books/</guid>
      <description>This page lists the known books about Apache Camel. If you happen to know a book which is not listed, then please contact us (i.e., using the Mailing Lists).&#xA;Cloud Native Integration with Apache Camel Camel in Action 2nd edition Camel in Action Apache Camel Developer&amp;rsquo;s Cookbook Camel Design Patterns Mastering Apache Camel Instant Apache Camel Message Routing Instant Apache Camel Messaging System Enterprise Integration Patterns Cloud Native Integration with Apache Camel Cloud Native Integration with Apache Camel by Guilherme Camposo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Camel Extra components</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/camel-extra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/camel-extra/</guid>
      <description>Camel Extra project contains a number of extension components which due to GPL/LGPL licensing cannot be hosted at Apache.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contributing</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for expressing your interest in contributing to Apache Camel, a versatile open-source integration framework. Apache Camel consists of various subprojects, each with its own specific contribution guidelines. To ensure a smooth and effective contribution process, it is important to familiarize yourself with the guidelines specific to the subproject you intend to contribute to. Check the pages for each of the subprojects for details about how to contribute:&#xA;Camel Core Camel K Camel Kafka Connector Camel Karaf Camel Quarkus Camel Spring Boot If in doubt about where to start, check the contributing guide from Camel Core, which provides the overall guidelines for the project and contains comprehensive documentation that may apply for the subprojects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mailing Lists</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/mailing-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/mailing-list/</guid>
      <description>Read this first before posting Mailing lists basics To email the mailing list, you need to subscribe first by sending an email to the Subscribe email address listed below.&#xA;If you do not wish to receive any more emails, send a message to the Unsubscribe email address listed below.&#xA;If you do not subscribe to the mailing list, your email will be sent to the moderation queue and most likely it will be rejected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sources</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/sources/</guid>
      <description>Using GitHub The source code is mirrored to GitHub, so you can also check out the source code from GitHub, if you are familiar with using GitHub.&#xA;By using GitHub, you can submit pull requests to the project using the standard GitHub way.&#xA;https://github.com/apache/camel/ Checking out from git git clone https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf/camel.git Only project developers can commit to git via this method. SSH must be installed on your client machine. Enter your site password when prompted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/support/</guid>
      <description>Getting help If you are experiencing problems using Camel, then please report your problem to our mailing list or the Zulip chat. This allows the entire community to help with your problem. If indeed a bug has been identified in the Camel software, then document the problem in our Issue Tracker. Please refrain from immediately opening a ticket in the issue tracker unless you are certain it&amp;rsquo;s a problem in the Camel software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/team/</guid>
      <description>This page lists who we are. By all means add yourself to the list. Let&amp;rsquo;s sort it in alphabetical order&#xA;Committers Name ID Organisation Aaron Mulder ammulder Chariot Solutions Akitoshi Yoshida ay SAP Andrea Cosentino acosentino Red Hat Antonin Stefanutti astefanutti Red Hat Babak Vahdat bvahdat Cyberlogic Consulting GmbH Ben O&amp;rsquo;Day boday Initek Consulting Bilgin Ibryam bibryam Bob Paulin bob Bruce Snyder bsnyder Charles Moulliard cmoulliard Red Hat Christian Mueller cmueller Amazon Web Services Christian Posta ceposta Solo Christian Schneider cschneider Claus Ibsen davsclaus Red Hat Colm O hEigeartaigh coheigea Talend David Jencks djencks IBM Daniel Kulp dkulp Talend Denis Istomin distomin Dmitry Volodin dmvolod T-Systems RUS Franz Forsthofer forsthofer SAP Freeman Fang ffang Red Hat Gary Tully gtully Red Hat Gert Vanthienen gertv Gregor Zurowski gzurowski Independent consultant Guillaume Nodet gnodet Red Hat Hadrian Zbarcea hadrian Henryk Konsek hekonsek Hiram Chirino chirino Red Hat Ioannis Canellos iocanel Red Hat Jacek Laskowski jlaskowski James Carman jcarman Savoir Technologies Jan Bednar janbednar CGI IT Czech Republic Jean-Baptiste Onofré jbonofre Huawei Jeff Genender jgenender Savoir Technologies Jeremy Ross jeremyross Elevation Solutions Johan Edstrom joed Savoir Technologies John Poth Red Hat Jonathan Anstey janstey Red Hat James Netherton Red Hat James Strachan jstrachan Karen Lease klease Luca Burgazzoli lburgazzoli Red Hat Marat Gubaidullin mgubaidullin Talisman Cloud Martin Krasser krasserm Nicky Sandhu nsandhu Nicola Ferraro nicolaferraro Redpanda Onder Sezgin onders Omar Al-Safi oalsafi Otavio Rodolfo Piske orpiske Red Hat Quinn Stevenson quinn Raul Kripalani raulk Pascal Schumacher pascalschumacher Pasquale Congiusti pcongiusti Red Hat Peter Palaga ppalaga Red Hat Rhuan Rocha rhuanrocha Digibee Rich Newcomb rnewcomb Richard Kettelerij rickette Avisi BV Rob Davies rajdavies Roman Kalukiewicz romkal Scott England-Sullivan sully6768 Red Hat Stan Lewis slewis Red Hat Tadayoshi Sato tsato Red Hat Tomohisa Igarashi igarashitm Red Hat Tracy Snell tjsnell Juice Labs Willem Jiang ningjiang Huawei William Tam wtam Red Hat Zineb Bendhiba zbendhiba Red Hat Zheng Feng zhfeng Red Hat Zoran Regvart zregvart Red Hat Contributors If you have been contributing to the Apache Camel project, and you want your name added to the list below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Stories</title>
      <link>https://camel.apache.org/community/user-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camel.apache.org/community/user-stories/</guid>
      <description>This page is intended as a place to collect user stories and feedback on Apache Camel. If you are using or have tried Apache Camel please add an entry or comment; or post to the mailing list.&#xA;Company, Product, or Project Description Alpakka Alpakka uses Apache Camel to implement additional messaging interfaces for actors. Any Camel component can be used to send and receive messages from Akka actors. For details, refer to the documentation of the extension module.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
